jbe-platform.com 2018-08-07

# John Benjamins e-Platform: Privacy policy

**John Benjamins Publishing Company** (“Benjamins”, “we”, “us” or “our”) is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy online. 

This privacy statement describes which personal data we collect or receive from you and how that is processed by us or on our behalf. Personal data means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. 

By visiting our JB e-Platform you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this statement.

We may review this privacy policy based on feedback from users or changes in legal requirements, so please check back here regularly for the latest version.

Questions and comments regarding this privacy statement should be addressed to the Privacy Team at John Benjamins Publishing Company, P.O.Box 36224, NL-1020 ME Amsterdam, The Netherlands, or by email to: _privacy@benjamins.nl_  

### Data we process

We will collect and process the following personal data about you:

  1. Information you give us: This is information about you that you give us when filling in forms on our site or by corresponding with us by phone, e-mail or otherwise. This includes information you provide when you register to use our site, subscribe to our services, or sign up for email alerts. The information you give us may include your name, address, e-mail address, phone number, financial and credit card information, and institution and / or affiliation.
  2. Information we collect about you: With regard to your visits to our site we may automatically collect technical information, including the internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the internet, your login information, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, screen resolution, operating system and platform. See also the cookie information.
  3. Information we receive about you from other sources: We are also working closely with third parties (including, for example, business partners, sub-contractors in technical, payment and delivery services, analytics providers, search information providers, credit reference agencies) and may receive information about you from them.

We do not process any special categories of personal data, meaning personal data revealing racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, genetic or biometric data that uniquely identifies you, data concerning your health, sex life or sexual orientation. We do not process data relating to criminal convictions or offences or related security measures unless legally obliged to do so.  

### The purposes for which we process data

We do not sell, share or transfer personal information except as set out in this privacy notice. 

We may process your data to **enter into contracts** with you. Where you ask us to provide services to you, we will process your personal data so that we can deliver these services to you. Our use of personal data in this way includes sharing your personal data with our employees and other personnel, partner agencies, suppliers and sub-contractors such as credit reference agencies. Such processing is necessary for us to be able to enter into and perform the contract for the supply of services you have requested from us and this is the legal basis for such processing. If you do not wish to provide us with your personal data in this way, you will be unable to receive services from us.

We may process your personal data in order to provide various supporting **customer services** to you (such as where you contact us with a question in connection with our services and / or request certain information from us). The legal basis on which we process your personal data in these circumstances is our respective legitimate interests of providing or receiving customer services and communicating with you. If you do not provide us with the personal data we request from you for customer services purposes, we may not be able to fully answer your queries.

We may process your personal data in order to provide you with a more tailored **user experience**. We may also use your personal data to make sure our site is displayed in the most effective way for the device you are using. We also use various cookies to help us improve our site (see also the section on cookies). We will also process personal data for the purposes of making our site more secure, and to administer our site and for internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes. The legal basis on which we process personal data in these circumstances is our legitimate interest to provide you with the best customer experience we can, and to ensure that our site is kept secure.

We may process your personal data for **marketing** purposes after you have expressly opted in to receive marketing communications from us. The legal basis for the processing of your data is your explicit permission. We may also use data that you have given us to provide you with information about other goods and services we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about. In that case, the legal basis is our legitimate interest to develop our services and grow our business.

In certain circumstances we may also need to share your personal data if we are under a duty to disclose or share personal data in order to comply with any **legal obligation** , or in order to enforce or apply our terms and conditions of use and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety, of us, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction. 

We do not sell personal information to any third parties, unless it is included in the **sale of (part of) our business** to another party. For instance, if we would sell a journal to another publisher, the subscriber list and information about archive access rights might be included.

We retain the information that we have about you only for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, and to satisfy any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.   

### Rights

  1. You have the right to ask us not to process your personal information for marketing purposes. You can ask us to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by following the opt-out links on any marketing message sent to you, or by contacting us.
  2. You have the right to ask us to correct any incorrect personal information that we store about you. It is important that this personal information is accurate and current, so please keep us informed if your personal information changes during your relationship with us. 
  3. You have the right to ask us for an electronic copy of the personal information that we store about you. 
  4. You have the right to ask us to delete personal information (‘right to be forgotten’) that we hold about you. Please note that this may also mean that we will no longer be able to provide you with services that are linked to your personal access rights.

Please email us at _privacy@benjamins.nl_ to request your information, to provide us with correct information, or to ask for information to be deleted from our systems.

In principle, this will be done free of charge, but we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. 

In order to perform any of these requests, we are obliged to confirm your identity, and we may need to ask specific information from you for that purpose. We may also contact you for further information in relation to your request.

We aim to respond to all legitimate requests within 30 days. If your request is complicated, it may take us longer, but in that case we will let you know about this within 30 days and we will keep you updated on the progress.  

### Security

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal information from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. Access to your personal information is limited to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They process the information on our behalf. 

Our site uses up-to-date industry procedures to keep personal information as secure as possible. Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely safe; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

Where you are using functionality behind a password login, it is your responsibility to keep your password confidential.  

### Cookies

We use cookies that are essential for the operation of our website, such as cookies that enable you to log into secure areas of our site, manage your own preferences and settings, or use the shopping cart.

Analytical or performance cookies allow us to see how visitors use our site and move through it. This information is used by us to monitor the performance and improve the quality of our site. For this purpose, we use Google Analytics; the information is transmitted to Google and stored on their servers in the USA. We do not use this information to track specific persons or to combine it with other personal information, only to see how the site is used in general. Although Google Analytics plants a permanent cookie on your web browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit the site, the cookie cannot be used by anyone but Google. Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to this site is restricted by the [Google Analytics Terms of Service](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html) and the [Google Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en).

We also use social media buttons and/or plugins on this site that allow you to connect with your social network in various ways. For these to work, social media sites including Facebook, Twitter, Digg, Bibsonomy, Reddit, will set cookies through our site which may be used to enhance your profile on their site or contribute to the data they hold for various purposes outlined in their respective privacy policies.

You can block cookies by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of our site.  

### Links to other sites

Our site may include links to third-party websites. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for these websites or their policies. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please check their privacy notices before you submit any personal information to them.  

### Contact

For the purposes of the General Data Protection Regulation (EU 2016/679), the data controller is John Benjamins Uitgeverij B.V., doing business as John Benjamins Publishing Company, Klaprozenweg 75-g, NL-1033 NN Amsterdam, The Netherlands; Chamber of Commerce Amsterdam 33235162.

Questions and concerns about our handling of your personal data may be addressed to the Privacy Team at John Benjamins Publishing Company, P.O.B. 36224, NL-1020 ME Amsterdam, The Netherlands, or by email to: _privacy@benjamins.nl_

You have the right to file a complaint with or ask for mediation by the Dutch supervisory authority ‘Autoriteit Persoonsgegevens’, if you are not satisfied with the way we are handling your personal data or have responded to your requests or inquiries about this. They can be contacted at: Autoriteit Persoonsgegevens, P.O.B. 93374, NL-2509 AJ The Hague, The Netherlands. <https://autoriteitpersoonsgegevens.nl/en>  

**This privacy policy was last updated on 23 May 2018.**
